人之表象
Everything that you conceive of yourself as being
皆为虚妄
is an illusion.
自我亦为虚妄
There is no self.
深吸一口气
Take a deep breath in.
感触万物
Allow yourself to experience everythingness
一切皆空
and nothingness.
呼气  摒弃恐惧
As you breathe out, let go of fear.
超脱俗世
You can choose to leave the familiar...
我没事
I'm fine.
或安于遗忘
...or stay in the safe oblivion
-痛苦  无知  -唐娜
- of pain, ignorance... - Donna.
-抱歉  抱歉  -和空虚
- Sorry. I'm sorry. - and a blank page.
-我们需要很多冰鲜虾  -两千块
- We need a lot of shrimp on ice. - $2,000?
最好是白对虾
Gulf white, preferably.
不要冻的  大家会尝出来的
And not frozen 'cause people will know.
花两千块买虾
But two grand for shrimp?
你要把人淹没在虾海里吗
What, are you gonna try to drown someone in 'em?
-太疯狂了  -想大展拳脚的公司
- It's crazy. - Anyone who means anything
都会开个丰盛的派对
throws a lavish party.
而在展览会  虾就是丰盛的代名词
At COMDEX, lavish equals shrimp.
-我们租到好展位了吗  -正在办
- Did we get a decent booth location? - I'm on hold right now.
-展位要花多少  -一万八
- Well, how much is that gonna cost? - 18 grand.
你不问我一堆问题吗
You're not gonna ask me 50 questions?
这点钱就吓住你了吗
You gonna blow the balls off the numbers?
是啊  喂  你好
Yes, sir. Yes, hello.
没错  27号到2号  抱歉  能稍等下吗
That's correct. 27th through the 2nd. I'm sorry, can you hold?
梅琳  这部电话也有静电干扰
Maylene, this phone is clicking now, too.
-你能找人来修修吗  -好的
- Can you get someone in here to fix it? - Yes, sir.
喂  抱歉久等  是几号展位
Hello, sorry about that. What is it?
C23  谢谢
C-23. Thank you.
康懋达  坦迪公司  卡迪夫电子
Commodore, Tandy, Cardiff Electric.
太棒了  太棒了
That is huge, that is huge.
那地方可大了  我去过
It's so big, I'm telling you. I've been there.
你还好吧
You all right?
你去不成展览会不失望吗
You're not upset about COMDEX?
什么
What?
我为什么会想去展览会
Why would I want to go to COMDEX?
不都是推销员去吗
It's just for salesmen, right?
他们开机就能看到我的作品
They can just turn it on to see what I did.
也是
True.
我走了会想你的
You know, I'll miss you while I'm there.
我也是
Yeah, me, too.
你告诉戈登了吗
You tell Gordon yet?
一直拖着没说  你觉得他会生气吗
I keep putting it off. You think he'll be upset?
戈登·克拉克吗
Gordon Clark?
计算机分销商展览
COMDEX.
-真是太棒了  对吧  -你说是就是咯
- Pretty amazing, huh? - I'll take your word for it.
真的很难跟没去过的人解释清楚
Well, it's hard to explain if you haven't actually been there.
我不想夸大其词
I mean, I don't want to oversell it or anything,
不过真的很壮观
but it is spectacular.
今年会有一千多个展位
There's gonna be over a thousand booths this year.
所有大人物都会到场
All the heavy hitters show up.
史蒂夫·乔布斯  比尔·盖茨  米切尔·卡普尔You got Steve Jobs, Bill Gates, Mitch Kapor, you know?
苹果
微软
莲花软件
IBM包下两层酒店房间  还有派对
IBM takes over two hotel floors, and the party scene--
派对简直难以置信
the party scene is unbelievable.
我和唐娜81年去的时候
Donna and I were there in '81,
从顶楼开始  一路逛下来
we started at the penthouse and worked our way down,
把每个有像样展位的公司的派对都逛了一遍
hitting every corporate party with decent booths.
你在诺威克酒店给我们订了房间  对吧
You got us rooms at the Norwick, right?
住那里很重要
'Cause staying there is key,
否则排队等出租车就得等一个礼拜
otherwise you spend the whole week waiting in line for a taxi.
相信我  我有经验
Trust me, I know.
当时可真是不堪回首
I learned the hard way.
等等  你也要去吗
Wait, are you going, too?
乔说只需要一间房
Joe said he only needed one room.
你不带我去展览会吗
You're going to COMDEX without me?
抱歉  决定那会儿你病了没来上班
I'm sorry. It was arranged the week you were out sick.
-我忘了告诉你  -少骗人了
- I forgot to tell you. - Bullshit you forgot to tell me!
卡梅伦也不会去
Cameron's not going either.
卡梅伦也不去就行了是吧
Oh, well, if Cameron's not going, then all right, then.
你没必要去的
Look, it's not like your role is essential.
是啊  我只是造出了那东西而已  乔
Yeah, I only built the damn thing, Joe.
展览会是要推销电脑  那是我的专长
COMDEX is about selling it and that is my area of expertise.
演示怎么办  系统出故障了怎么办
What about the demo? What if there's a glitch in the system?
就像你推出交响乐时那样吗
Like when you debuted the Symphonic?
我本不想提这事
I was trying to avoid bringing it up,
但大家还记得81年发生了什么
but the fact is, people still remember what happened in '81.
我不能让那事影响潜在的买家
I can't afford to have the stink from that distracting potential buyers.
但如果我需要故障检修  一定先打给你
But if I need any troubleshooting, you're my first call.
我这几个月拼死拼活
I didn't kill myself all these months
可不是为了让你摘果子
for you to get all the glory with the Giant.
周一C23展位我是去定了
You plan on seeing me at booth C-23 on Monday.
呼气  摒弃恐惧
...breathe out, let go of fear.
超脱俗世...
You can choose to leave the familiar or stay...
亨特
Hunt?
你来这儿干什么
What are you doing here?
唐娜
Donna, hey.
-你在外面站多久了  -就一会儿
- How long have you been out here? - Not long.
我只是...
I was just, um...
-我不该来的  -不  我只是...
- This was a mistake. - No, no. I just--
我以为卢博克市那事之后...
I thought after Lubbock that--
我不该来这儿
I shouldn't be here.
你能当作没在这儿见过我吗
could you just forget you ever saw me?
当然  不用担心
Of course. You don't have to worry.
但你真的不能再这么跑来了
But you really can't show up like this.
我明白  不会再发生这种事了
I know, it won't-- it won't happen again.
我保证
I promise.
唐娜  我希望你知道
Donna... I want you to know
我认为你是个了不起的女人
I think you're an amazing woman.
一切都还好吧
Everything all right over there?
不久前看到你们挖开了后院草坪
Noticed you guys had to dig up your back lawn a while back,
全部重铺了
resod everything.
我只是想确认下不是因为出现了
Just wanna make sure there's not some sort of ugly weed
我需要留意的讨厌杂草
I need to look out for.
没有  天气太热有部分草死了
Oh, uh, no. The heat killed off some patches.
我们没浇够水
We just didn't water enough.
这样
Oh, yeah.
唐娜
Donna?
我需要和你谈谈
I need to talk to you.
我知道我们约定过
Look, I know we promise
任何大于50的支出都要预先讨论
to discuss any purchases over $50,
但在你爆发前  我想说这次是紧急情况
but before you explode, this was an emergency situation
我当时必须马上采取行动
and I had to act fast.
什么紧急情况
What do you mean, emergency?
乔要撇下我自己去参加计算机分销商展览
Joe's trying to box me out of COMDEX
我不用跟你说他有多阴险
and I don't have to tell you what a snake he is,
拉斯维加斯主街上只剩下一间空房
but there was only one room left on the Strip
飞往那儿的航班也爆满
and flights to Vegas were shooting up.
我不得不用我们的信用卡透支了455美元
I had to put the $455 charge on our credit card.
我只是...我必须得去
I just-- I have to be there.
既然你需要  那就花吧
Whatever you need to do.
你确定
Oh, are-are you sure?
唐娜  你最好了
Donna, you're the best.
天呐  谢谢你
Oh, my God. Thank you.
我要去看看我该带哪套西装了
Oh, I gotta figure out what suit I need to bring.
我知道你觉得我穿蓝色好看
Look, I know you think I look good in blue,
但我可不想被人当做是IBM的人
but I don't want to risk anyone thinking I'm with IBM, you know?
-早安  梅琳  -约翰...
- Morning, Maylene. - John...
亲爱的  你知道我得等喝了咖啡
Now, sweetheart, you know I can't talk business
才能讨论工作的
till I get my "Ker-fee" in me.
内森  我不知道你要过来
Nathan, well, I didn't realize you were coming by.
需要喝点什么吗
Can I get you anything?
来杯咖啡吧  梅琳知道喜欢加什么
Cup of joe. Maylene knows how you like it.
不用了
I'm fine right here.
什么风把你刮来的
Wh-- what brings you by?
不久前你为了这个个人电脑项目跟我要钱
A little while back you asked me for money for this PC project.
如果我没记错的话  你没答应
Oh, you told me to shove it, if I remember correctly.
幸亏了  我周转了一下资金
Thank goodness you did. I was able to shift some things around--
我重新考虑了一下
I've reconsidered.
这样啊
I see.
我想  既然我的老朋友约翰·博斯沃思
I thought if my old pal John Bosworth
想从我这儿得到点什么
wants something from me,
我就应该给他
I should give it to him.
这个时间就喝酒太早了点吧  约翰
A little early in the day for a drink, ain't it, John?
你在取笑我吗  内森
You havin' fun, Nathan?
博斯  我们刚刚...
Hey, Boz, we just got a--
你以为你是谁  就这么大摇大摆走进来
Who the hell do you think you are, waltzing in here like this?
-什么  -你叫什么名字来着
- What? - What is your name again?
-卡梅伦  -滚出我的办公室  卡梅伦
- Cameron. - Get the hell out of my office, Cameron.
你以为我门口坐个秘书是干嘛的
Why do you think I have a damn secretary?
-不要让我再说第二遍  -好吧
- Don't make me say it again! - All right.
约翰  你今天有点暴躁啊  是不是
My God, John. You're a bit jumpy today, aren't you?
你不介意的话  我要开会去了
If you don't mind, I got a meeting.
卡迪夫电子  巨人
我主要担心的是
My main concern is
要如何将这款产品与其他兼容机区分开
differentiating this from the other PC compatibles.
记者会把它与其他产品混为一谈
Press will want to lump it in with all the others.
卡梅伦写的操作系统
Well, Cameron's operating system
和市面上任何一款电脑都不同
is unlike anything else on the market.
卡梅伦
Cameron?
没错  它是交互式的
Uh, yeah, it's interactive.
我可以给你们展示一下
Um, I can just show it to you.
你们策略不对
You're barking up the wrong tree.
你们想要这台机器
No, you want this machine to stand out
能在展会上脱颖而出
from every other machine on the floor,
就不要再说这台机器如何
you gotta stop talking about the machine
而是应当讲讲造它的人
and you gotta start talking about the people that made it.
他们为此呕心沥血
They bled for this.
不管我们愿不愿意  未来都会降临
The future's coming whether we like it or not,
但没人说它会与我们有关
but it ain't written anywhere that it includes any of us.
而想要在其中有一席之地是要付出代价的
And getting there ain't free. There's a cost.
那些投资者想要独揽功劳
People who put up the money, they like to take the credit,
但功劳属于建造它的人
but the credit belongs to them that built it.
这台机器  就是未来
This machine is the future.
让他们明白这一点
Make them see that.
约翰·博斯沃思  你被捕了
John Bosworth, you're under arrest.
我们能去外面说吗
Can we do this outside?
-我们就在这儿说  -发生什么了
- We're gonna do this right here. - What the hell's going on?
-坐下  先生  -确保没人碰电脑
- Sit down, sir. - Make sure no one touches these computers.
所有人  请冷静  待在原地不要动
Everyone, please be calm and stay where you are.
我们要关闭这家公司
We're gonna be shutting this company down.
只要我们的公务完成
Once we have what we need,
你们就可以在搜身完后离开
you'll be searched and cleared to leave.
任何公司财产都不允许带离
No company property will be allowed to leave the premises.
现在  请耐心等待
For now, just sit tight.
我们会尽快让你们离开
We'll have you outta here as soon as possible.
请各位离开键盘
Step back from your keyboards, folks.
不要再打字了  谢谢
Stop typing, please.
待在原地  小心
Stay where you are. Heads up.
他们认为是约翰干的吗
They think John did it?
试试那扇门
Go try that door over there.
你有这个房间的钥匙吗
Do you have a key to this room?
有
Yes.
开门
Come on.
先生  请拿上个人物品离开这间屋子
Sir, take your personal belongings and get out.
-可是我  -快
- But I -- - Now.
把那个拿出去
Get that out of here.
他没在  我会告诉他你来过
He's not in. I'll tell him you stopped by.
没事  谢谢  不用了
Oh, no, thank you. That's fine.
我一会儿再来找他吧
I'll just -- I'll catch up with him later.
既然来了  顺便在他的告别卡上签个名吧
Oh, as long as you're here, I need you to sign his goodbye card.
告别卡
Goodbye card?
你不知道吗  你俩看起来走得挺近呢
You didn't hear? You two seemed so close.
-他是  被调职了吗  -他辞职的
- Was he -- was he transferred? - Resigned.
而且很突然
Would've been nice to have a little notice.
祝你一切顺利  心想事成
他有没有说要去哪里  离开达拉斯吗
Did he say where he was going? Is he leaving Dallas?
他没说我也没问
He didn't say and I didn't ask.
你知道什么消息吗
Do you know anything?
我们去你家吧  弄清是怎么回事
Let's go back to your place, figure it out.
好  我家见
All right, I'll see you there.
他们在找电脑入侵  计算机犯罪的证据
They're looking for evidence of hacking, computer crime.
不可能是博斯沃思干的
Bosworth couldn't do that.
他认识的人中大概有三个能做到
He knows maybe three people who could.
你参与了吗
Are you a part of this?
博斯沃思找的我  行了吧
Bosworth came to me, okay?
他问我了不了解414黑客和入侵电脑
He asked if I knew about the 414s, about hacking.
真的很简单
It was so easy.
他们简直就...
They were practically -- like,
银行没有任何保护措施
the bank has no security whatsoever.
对不起
I'm sorry.
本来打算是等计算机分销商展览结束
We were gonna put all the money back in Cardiff's account
一销售出去  有了利润就把钱还给卡迪夫
as soon as we made some sales and we came back from COMDEX.
我们以为他不会发现的
I mean, we thought he'd never notice.
大家都出去
Everybody out.
只是个误会
It's all a misunderstanding.
不是误会
It's not a misunderstanding.
过不了一天我们就会把这事当笑料了
We'll be laughing about this in 24 hours.
戈登  你错了
Gordon, you're wrong.
怎么回事
What's going on?
-你知道这事吗  -我完全不知道
- Did you know about this? - I didn't know anything about this.
你知道  你参与了
Yes, you did. You were involved.
-我没有  -你有
- I was not involved. - Yes, you were.
-你肯定参与了  -是我干的
- You were involved from the -- - I did it.
我是想拯救公司
I was trying to save the company.
我们没有资金了
We were completely out of money.
你俩简直是绝配
You two are perfect for each other.
-你俩都是疯子  -如果我没这么做
- You're both psychotic. - If I hadn't done this,
我们几周前就关门大吉了
we would've been shut down weeks ago.
你所有的努力都将化为乌有
All your work would've been shelved.
别一副你做了义卖的模样  你抢了银行
Don't act like you threw a bake sale. You robbed a bank.
那只是卡迪夫的钱
It was Cardiff's money.
只要把电脑卖出去
Once we sold the computer,
我们就能把钱还上  还能挣钱...
we would've made it back and then some...
你应该先来问我  我们可以做个计划
You should've come to me. We could've made a plan.
现在倒好  所有人的工作都不保了
Now all of our careers are in jeopardy.
你还在想工作  我可能要进监狱了
Your careers? I could be going to jail.
你们俩真是  我太傻了  傻到家了
Oh, my God, you two. I'm so stupid. God, I'm stupid.
别扯上我  我和你一样生气
Stop including me in this. I'm just as upset as you are.
你到最后肯定会得利的
No, you're gonna come out on top of this somehow.
每次有坏事发生  你都能从中获益
Every time something terrible happens, you seem to benefit.
比如IBM发现我们逆向他们电脑的时候
IBM finding out we reverse engineered their PC,
卡梅伦弄丢她写的BIOS代码的时候
Cameron losing her work on the BIOS.
-什么  -没错
- What? - Oh, yeah.
他是为了宣传故意为之
He crashed it for publicity
然后看着你独自痛苦
and let you twist in the wind.
你们在床上说悄悄话时他没提起吗
Did he fail to mention that to you during pillow talk?
是真的吗
Is that true?
我看告发博斯的就是你
I'll bet you're the one that turned Boz in.
-这样你就是老大了  -乔  回答我
- Now you're top dog. - Joe, answer me.
没错  我是为了宣传  而且成功了
Yes, I did it. For publicity, which we got.
很抱歉为了我们的项目让你难过了
I'm sorry you had a bad day for the sake of our project.
-就难过而已吗  -你现在有什么资格
- "A bad day"? - Are you really in a place
指责别人
to cast judgment right now?
而且你攻击我干嘛  戈登
And why the hell are you attacking me, Gordon?
-偷钱的是她  -我为它献出了全部生活
- She stole the money! - I put my life into that box.
我就没有吗
Like I didn't?
你不过起了个名字  加了个手柄
You gave it a name and a handle.
根本没什么是你造的
You didn't build a damn thing.
他说的对  你只会搞破坏
He's right. You only destroy things.
你从来没有创造过什么
You've never created anything.
你们俩的现在就是我创造的
I created both of you.
那么  一切都完了吗
So, it's over? Everything?
我们又
We're back to--
我们全白忙活了吗
we're back to where we started?
老天
Oh, my God, I--
真不敢相信又撞上这种事了
I can't believe this is happening again.
德州仪器那边还有职缺吗
Any openings at TI?
唐娜  我该怎么办
Donna, what do I do?
戈登  抱歉  我现在
Gordon, I'm sorry. I-- I just--
我现在没心思想这事
I can't deal with this right now.
唐娜
Donna...?
抱歉  我还有会
I'm sorry, I have a meeting.
唐娜
Donna?
我没准又得去我爸妈家睡沙发了
I might end up crashing on my parents' couch again.
我听说他拿钱去还赌债了
I heard he took the money to pay off gambling debts.
赌马欠的  他赌马上瘾
Horse racing. He's an addict.
这种人就该送进牢里修理修理
Jail should be a good place to work on that.
所以还是得雇老派靠得住的人
That's why you don't hire some ancient good old boy
来经营你的电脑生意
to run your computer business.
他肯定得被关一阵子了
I bet they send him away for a while.
至少接下来十年里
At least he knows where his meals are coming from
他不用愁饭吃
for the next 10 years.
你跟他谈过编码的事吗
You ever talk to him about code?
-就跟猿人似的不开化  -他就是一垃圾
- He's like a caveman. - He's a scumbag.
-你好  -乔·麦克米伦  卡迪夫电子
-  Hello? - Joe MacMillan, Cardiff Electric.
-你还好吗  吉姆  -你好啊  乔
- How you doing, Jim? - Oh, hey, Joe.
今年你去拉斯维加斯参展吗
We gonna see you out in Vegas this year?
我就是为这个找你
That's just what I'm calling you about.
我想给你个机会提前赚一笔
I wanted to give you an opportunity to get in early.
赶在参展后身价大涨之前  先订一小单
A small order now, before COMDEX, before the prices skyrocket.
我们还是打算进IBM的
I think we're gonna stick with IBM.
但是他们的电脑不便携啊
But IBM doesn't make a portable.
有  但是还没宣布
Well, not one they've announced yet.
这传言你从哪听来的
Where did you hear this rumor?
不知道  人人都这么说
I don't know. Everybody's talking about it.
-发布日期定下了吗  -明年上半年吧
- Is there a release date? - I hear early next year.
-太谢谢你了  吉姆  -没事  客气
- Thank you, Jim. - Sure. You bet.
总算把她们哄睡了
I finally got them down.
你也去睡会儿吧  亲爱的
Why don't you go to sleep, sweetheart?
你脸色很不好
You look terrible.
不了  我想等戈登回来
No, I want to wait until Gordon gets home.
-他打电话了吗  -还没
- Has he called yet? - No.
这种事是不是越来越多  自从...
This kinda thing been happening a lot since--
自从他在自家后院里挖坑吗
Since he dug a hole in our back yard?
妈  这种事从我们认识起就很寻常了
Mom, this kind of thing has been happening since the day we met.
我就是一问  亲爱的
I'm just asking, sweetheart.
至少工作还顺利吧
Work okay, at least?
亨特不在德州仪器干了
Hunt is leaving TI.
我的天  他怎么了
Oh, my goodness. What happened?
-被炒了吗  -不  他自己辞职了
- Did he get fired? - No, he resigned.
-也没提前说  -他在那里干得很好啊
- No notice. - Well, they love him over there.
怎么突然就想起来辞职了呢
Why on earth would he do a thing like that?
妈  我可能犯了个错误
Mom, I think I made a mistake.
我们在卢博克出差的时候
When we were in Lubbock...
这种事是难免的
Something like this was bound to happen.
妈  我没跟他上床
Mom, I didn't sleep with him.
那究竟是怎么了  亲爱的
Then what are we really talking about here, honey?
我不知道  我也不知道  我只是
I don't know. I don't know. I just--
我以为他对我没兴趣呢
I thought-- I thought he wasn't interested,
但他昨晚跑来我家外面
but then he was here last night, outside the house.
-然后呢  -也没发生什么
- And? - Well, nothing, really.
他慌了神  然后就走了
He got all flustered and left,
而且我觉着他在外面站了好一会儿了
and I think he'd been out there for a while.
戈登知道吗
Does Gordon know?
妈  我该怎么办
Mom, what am I gonna do?
你爸和我爱你
Your daddy and I love you,
我们也爱戈登  因为你爱他
and we love Gordon because you love him,
但看看你这惨样
but here you are, miserable,
整天拼死拼活地维持家庭
continuing to hold up this entire household
而他却不知道哪去了
while he's off God knows where.
我们会一直支持你
We will continue to support you
尽我们所能帮助你
and help you any way we can,
我们乐意照顾你到死
and we'll do so gladly until we die.
但是唐娜  你得认真地想一想
But, Donna, you need to think long and hard
为什么事情总是回到这里
about why we keep ending up back here.
你得好好为你自己
And you need to figure out what is best
和孩子们想一想了
for you and for your children.
你在干什么呢
What are you doing?
嘿  亲爱的
Hey, honey.
那是巨人吗
Is that the Giant?
是  我还买了牛奶  咱家的喝完了
Yeah, and I also got milk. I noticed that we were out.
戈登这是你偷来的吗  这不是证物吗
Gordon, did you steal that? Isn't that evidence?
不不不  如果是的话  早就被收走了
No, no, no. If it was evidence, they would've seized it.
戈登  这可不好
Gordon, this is not good.
我不知道你怎么想的  但是
I don't know what you're thinking, but--
唐娜  你别一看见我就想什么
Donna, I need you to stop looking at me and thinking,
"又来了  又是交响乐的事重现"
"Here we go again. It's the Symphonic all over again."
-这回不一样  明白吗  -戈登
- 'Cause it's not, okay? - Gordon--
唐娜  真的不一样  我发誓
Look, Donna, it's not. I promise.
跟你说  这东西  就是一破烂
Look, this-- this right here, this is shit.
你当时制止我是对的
Okay, you were right to pull the plug.
你让你爸别再给我们钱是对的
You were right to tell your dad to stop giving us money.
你知道了  你知道多久...
You knew? How long did you know--
听着  我生了很久的气
Hey, hey, hey. Look, I was angry for a long time,
但我已经不气了
but I'm not anymore.
你做得对  好吗
You were right. Okay?
你担心我吗  是这样吗
Are you worried about me? Is that what this is?
这次不用你担心
Let me do the worrying this time, okay?
我没问题的  我有个计划
I got this. I have a plan, all right?
我会找到卡梅伦和乔
I'm gonna find Cameron and Joe
我们一起做  好吗
and we're gonna do this together, okay?
我需要他们  我自己做不来
I need them. I can't do this on my own.
什么事你自己做不来
You can't do what on your own?
去计算机分销商展览  我要去那儿
Go to COMDEX. I'm gonna go to COMDEX
卖掉"巨人"  就像我们计划的那样
and sell the Giant, just like we'd always planned.
去他的内森·卡迪夫
Damn Nathan Cardiff.
太疯狂了  你是在痴人说梦
That's crazy. That's insane.
我爱你  但卡梅伦现在都是通缉犯了
I love you, but Cameron is some sort of wanted criminal now.
-谁知道...  -我知道这很疯狂
- And who knows where-- - I know it's crazy.
但你也很疯狂啊
I know, but you're crazy, too.
你忘记了  但你是疯狂的
No, no, you forget that, but you are.
我们俩本来都很疯狂  但突然间
We were both crazy and then all of a sudden,
你就决定变理智了
you decided you needed to be the sane one.
-没错  因为...  -你需要照顾我  但你不用
- Yes, because-- - That you needed to take care of me, but you don't.
跟我一起疯狂吧
Look, be crazy with me.
我需要你做我的后盾  唐娜
I need you to be behind me, Donna.
这次我需要你支持我
I need you to support me on this.
我是你的后盾  戈登  你知道我总会支持你的
I am behind you, Gordon. You know that I'm here for you.
谢谢
Thank you.
程序员说卡梅伦可能去奥斯汀了
Listen, the coders think that Cameron went down to Austin.
如果我即刻动身  我明早就能到那儿
If I leave now, I can make it there by morning.
然后接上乔  再回来打包去计算机分销商展览
Then Joe, then back here to pack, then COMDEX.
我要卖电脑了
I'm gonna sell a computer.
我自己的电脑  就像我一直说的那样
My own computer, just like I always said I was.
我保证
I can promise you that.
我爱你
I love you.
-喂  -妈妈  是我
- Hello? - Mom, it's me.
甜心  出什么事了
Sweetheart, what's wrong?
你还好吗
Is everything okay?
我和孩子们要去跟你住段时间
The girls and I need to come and stay with you for a while.
好的  你跟戈登说过了吗
Okay. Have you talked to Gordon about this?
你能明天一大早来接她们吗
Can you just come pick them up first thing in the morning?
等戈登回家后  我想跟他谈谈
I'm gonna talk to Gordon when he gets home
到时我不希望孩子们在场
and I don't want them to be here when I do.
下一局是我的了
I got next game.
天呐  真后悔没亲眼看到你闯进卡迪夫电子
God, I would've paid money to see you break into Cardiff Electric.
乔知道"巨人"在你车库里吗
Does Joe know it's in your garage?
不  我先来找的你
No, I came to you first.
我知道我们工作上有很多摩擦
Look, I know that we've had less than an ideal working relationship,
有些时候是我不好
and I'll take some of the flak on that.
没错  生活上你对我也很混
Yeah, and you've been kind of a dick to me outside of work, too.
先看看我们有什么共识
Well, let's focus on what we do have in common.
如果我们还是把"巨人"拿去展览会呢
What if we take the Giant to COMDEX anyway?
吸引到很多买家
You know? And orders start coming in?
卡迪夫绝不会挡这种财路
I mean, Cardiff won't turn down that kind of money.
他会被迫恢复个人电脑部
He'll be forced to reopen the department.
你为什么非要我加入呢
Why do you even care if I come?
因为半台机器是你设计的
Because you are responsible for half the machine.
我们有才能  乔没有
We're the talent, not Joe.
不行  我惹上的麻烦已经够多了
No, I'm in enough trouble as it is.
那好吧  至少值得一试
Okay, okay. Well, it was worth a shot.
我想让你知道
And I want you to know that
虽然我们有分歧
even though that we've had our differences
我又不完全清楚
and I'm not entirely clear
你特殊操作系统的功能
on what the function of your special OS is,
但我会尽量在演示时弄好的
I'll try and do it justice at the demo.
我知道你想干嘛  我不吃这套
I know what you're doing. It's not gonna work.
好吧  那你听我说说
Okay, well, let me make sure I got it.
比微软磁盘操作系统更强大
It's better than MS-DOS because it does things
因为它会问候你
like ask you how your day is going
如果你指令错误  还会给你更正
and corrects you if you make a command wrong.
等等  我知道该怎么说了
Oh, wait, no, I know what I'll say.
就像电脑里住了你妈一样
It's like having your mother inside your computer.
怎么样
How's that?
开门啊  乔  我们知道你在里面
Come on, Joe. We know you're in there.
开门
Open up.
他可能在避风头
He's probably hiding.
我们现在怎么办
Well, what should we do now?
把这看做是我们不该插手的预兆吧
Take this as a sign we shouldn't be involved.
等等  别这样
Wait, wait, come on.
你身上有30块吗  我可没有
Do you have 30 grand on you? 'Cause I sure as hell don't,
而现在付我们展台  酒店房间
and right about now the checks for our booth,
和旅费的支票都没法兑现
our suite, and our trip have just bounced.
而且我们实话实说吧  他很会说话
And if we're really being honest with each other, he's not a bad talker.
你有他家钥匙
You have a key.
该死  他把家清空了  他跑了
Shit, he cleared out. He's gone.
他没跑  他家本来就这样
He's not gone, this is just how he lives.
故意的吗
On purpose?
天呐  我对这人真是毫不了解
God, I know nothing about this guy.
除了他喜欢玻璃
Other than he likes glass.
我要打给唐娜  我不想她担心
I'm gonna call Donna. I don't want her to worry.
你叫什么
唐娜
你好  唐娜  你想做什么
找到回去的路
抱歉  唐娜  我没找到"回去的路"这个程序
需要我做别的吗
不了  谢谢
你可真礼貌
我不记得了  都多久...
I don't remember. It's been--
得了吧  我想听听
Oh, come on. I wanna hear about it.
真的  我不记得了
Honestly, I don't even remember.
我告诉你我的第一次
I'll tell you my first time.
-好吧  -好
- Okay. - Okay...
是苹果二号
it was, um, the Apple II.
天呐  我觉得自己好老
Oh, God, jeez. I feel so old.
-不用了  -好
- I'm good. - All right.
我妈的新男友给我买的圣诞礼物
Uh, my mom's new boyfriend got it for me for Christmas.
就是想讨好我
Some pathetic attempt at winning me over.
到了新年的时候  我已经
But by New Year's I had disassembled it
把它拆装四次了
and reassembled it four times.
你拆开你妈的新男友用了多久
How long did it take you to disassemble your mom's new boyfriend?
他一直待到复活节呢
He hung in there till Easter.
你以前从未说起过你家人
You never really mention your family.
没什么可说的
There's not much to say.
好吧
Okay.
那是圣诞节前几周
Well, it was a few weeks before Christmas
我在《大众电子》的封面上看到了阿尔泰
and I saw the Altair on the cover of "Popular Electronics"
就一心想买到
and I just had to get the kit.
但我当时还在上学  已经欠了很多学生贷款
But I was in school and up to my ears in student loans,
又刚把钱都花在
and I'd just spent my last nickel
给唐娜买订婚戒指上了
on getting an engagement ring for Donna,
那可是笔寅吃卯粮的大钱
which cost serious money I didn't have.
我猜猜  大钻戒吗
Oh, let me guess. A big diamond.
我和唐娜以前会给彼此写情书
Me and Donna used to write each other these little love notes,
但都是加密的
but they were encrypted. We--
我们建立了自己的多字码密码
we developed our own polyalphabetic cipher...
真呆
Geeks.
总之  我自己设计了戒指
Anyways, I designed the ring myself
还把密码嵌在了上面
and incorporated the cipher into it,
要解开我们的密码
and the only way to break our code
就需要唐娜的订婚戒指
was with Donna's engagement ring.
等等  你用解码戒指跟你妻子求婚的
Wait, you proposed to your wife with a decoder ring?
-是啊  -戈登  天呐
- I know. - Gordon, wow.
我当时才23嘛
I was 23, you know?
她喜欢谜题什么的  这样挺好的
Anyways, she likes puzzles, and it was nice, you know?
有铂金有蓝宝石的
It was platinum with sapphires and stuff.
我本打算过节的时候给她
Anyways, I was gonna give it to her over the holidays.
但圣诞节那天
Well, Christmas Day comes
我去拿戒指  却找不到了
and I go to get the ring and it's gone.
你真该看到我当时的样子
You shoulda seen me.
我把整个公寓都翻了个底朝天  就为找戒指
I mean, I tore that apartment upside down looking for it.
唐娜拿着我的礼物进来了
And Donna comes in with my present
她冲我大吼
and she's yelling at me
让我别折腾公寓了  打开礼物
to stop ransacking the apartment and open it.
就是阿尔泰电脑
And there it was, the Altair computer kit.
我知道这钱不会是她跟她父母借的
And I knew she hadn't borrowed the money from her parents
因为她当时还没跟父母介绍过我
because she hadn't even told them about me yet.
你能相信吗
Would you believe
她找到了订婚戒指
that she found the engagement ring
然后当掉了戒指  给我买阿尔泰电脑
and pawned it to get me the Altair?
她还跟我说
And she said to me,
"等我们卖出第一台电脑你再给我买戒指吧"
"You can buy me a ring once we've sold our first PC."
哇
Yeah.
真难想象你和唐娜也曾是我这个年纪
It's hard to imagine you and Donna ever being my age.
我给她买来了
I got it for her.
什么  解码戒指吗
What, the decoder ring?
嗯  上周
Yeah, last week.
我知道我们一定能在计算机分销商展览上大获成功
I knew we were gonna nail it at COMDEX
卖掉巨人
and sell the Giant.
所以我找当年伯克利的那个珠宝师
So I had the same jeweler in Berkeley
又做了一个  寄到办公室
make one up and send it out to the office.
就藏在我车库里呢
It's hidden in my garage right now.
等下周回来  我要送给她
I'm gonna give it to her when I get back next week.
希望我们能卖掉巨人
I hope we sell the Giant.
能的
We will.
老天爷
Jesus.
你来干什么
What are you doing here?
我不久留  就来问你个问题
I'm not gonna stay. I just came to ask you a question.
你大老远跑来纽约就为问我个问题
You came all the way to New York to ask me a question?
我直视你的时候更容易分辨你的谎言
It's easier to tell when you're lying when I'm looking right at you.
-说吧  -IBM在开发便携电脑吗
- Let's have it. - Is IBM developing a portable PC?
是的
We are.
就为了打击我的电脑吗
So you could crush my machine?
就为了打击我吗
Crush me?
我跟那事毫无关系  项目团队在博卡
I had nothing to do with it. The team's down in Boca.
你就不能跟我实言相告  哪怕一次吗
For once, can you tell me the truth?
你或许会觉得震惊  乔
It may come as a shock to you, Joe,
但你并非宇宙的中心
but you're not the center of the universe.
就算我早知道你在建造便携电脑
Even if I knew you were making a portable,
你觉得我凭一己之力
you think I could alter the course
就能左右IBM这艘大航母的航向吗
of the aircraft carrier that is IBM,
逼他们建台便携电脑好打击你
make them build one just so I could hurt you?
你简直是疯了
You're out of your mind.
如果能让你好受点  我们离销售至少还有一年呢
If it makes you feel better, we're at lst a year away from market.
如果你是想问电脑的事  电话上说就行了
Now, if you wanted to ask me about computers, you could've called me,
所以你还是坐下  把你真实的目的告诉我吧
so why don't you have a seat and let me know why you're really here?
-我要的已经得到了  -坐下
- I got what I came for. - Sit down!
我们重新开始
Now... let's start again.
你四月之后一直在达拉斯
You've been in Dallas since April.
在那之前呢
Where were you before that?
你屈尊告诉我事实之后
After you deigned to tell me the truth,
我驱车走遍了全国
I drove across the country to figure out...
想要弄清楚我究竟更像你还是她
am I her son or your son?
即便她已经死了
Even if she was dead,
在那之前和你赶走她之后她必然有过一段人生
she must've lived an entire life after you sent her away.
她去过的地方  认识的人
Places she'd been, people who knew her.
我尽力找到每一个人
I talked to everyone I could,
想找到我身上属于她的那部分
trying to find the part of her that was me.
乔啊
Oh, Joe.
是因为我太像她吗
Do I remind you of her?
所以你才恨我吗
Is that why you hate me?
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你母亲
And I loved your mother.
你让我以为她抛弃了我
You let me think she abandoned me
还告诉我她死了
and then told me she was dead
可之后她还活了23年
23 years before she was.
我不要再跟你说这些了
I'm not going over this again.
我让她走是因为她差点害死你
I sent her away because she almost killed you.
是的  我为了保护你撒了谎
And, yes, yes, I lied to protect you.
她让你摔下屋顶啊
She let you fall, for heaven's sake!
至少她带我上去了
At least she took me up there.
因为她嗑药了
Because she was high.
她希望我成为梦想家
She wanted me to be a dreamer.
你妈妈才不是什么梦想家呢
Your mother wasn't a dreamer.
她只是迷惘
She was lost.
真正的梦想家  有才华的人
A real dreamer, someone that matters,
能凭空造出新东西
makes something out of nothing.
那全得靠努力
And that only happens with hard work.
这你是懂的
You understand that.
你一直懂这道理
You always have.
这方面你更像我
You're more like me in that regard,
谢天谢地
and thank God.
如果你搬回来  我能给你找个地方
Now, if you move back, I'll find a place for you.
你很快就能回归正轨
You'll be back on track soon enough.
在IBM干吗
At IBM?
人是健忘的
People have short memories.
我就不
Not me.
乔  我们都清楚
Joe, you and I both know
你总得回归现实
you have to come back down to earth eventually.
你已经来了
You're here now.
最难的部分已经过去了
The hard part's over.
我要做便携电脑项目的主要负责人
I need to be the primary on the portable.
管理整个项目
Run the whole thing.
如果这就是你要的  我会想办法
That's what you want, I'll figure it out.
很高兴你回来了  儿子
I'm glad you're back, son.
你怎么在这儿
What are you doing here?
我们昨晚来找你了
We came to look for you last night.
你在我床上睡了吗
Did you sleep in my bed?
是啊  你真该买个沙发
Yeah, you know, you should really get a couch.
我和唐娜...
You know, me and Donna have...
够了  我只是来拿东西的
Stop, I just came here to get my things.
你要走了
You're leaving?
我要回IBM去
I'm going back to IBM
造一台有一日能面市的便携电脑
to build a portable PC that will actually see the light of day.
你开我心吗
Are you kidding me?
我一开始就该这么做
It's what I should've done from the start.
你回IBM去  就是背叛自己的一切信仰
You go back to IBM, you go back on everything you stand for.
那就是你辜负我们了
That'll be you failing us.
我刚刚说了  是我错了
I just told you I was wrong.
我终于懂了  我终于懂你了
I finally get it. I finally get how you operate.
-好啊  滚吧  -不不
- Great, get out of my apartment. - No, no.
自始至终
Throughout this whole thing,
你总得控制一切  决定一切
you needed to be in control, make every decision.
你让公司每个人都按你的意思做
You have everybody at the company bow to your will.
但当你终于得到一个机会
But when you're finally faced with a real opportunity
做个梦想家  带大家打一场值得打的战役时
to be a visionary and lead in a battle that's worth fighting for,
你却决定离开
you're just gonna move on.
你这人真的很会说  乔
You know, you can spin a good word, Joe,
虽然你并不是工程师
even though you're not an engineer
更不是梦想家
and you are certainly no visionary,
但我没想到你居然会是个懦夫
but I never thought you were a coward.
你就不知道什么时候该闭嘴
And you never know when to shut your mouth!
说中了
Gotcha.
带着这股火气去展览会  我们一定能成功
Bring that fire to COMDEX and we'll kill.
-展览会  -想想啊
- COMDEX? - Think about it.
有几家公司的执行总裁上周被人铐走了
How many companies had their CEO hauled off in handcuffs last week?
展览会上有超过一千家参展者
There's over a thousand exhibitors there.
几乎不可能脱颖而出
It's nearly impossible to stand out in all that noise,
但人们一定会排队来看
but people will be lining up
乱得一塌糊涂的卡迪夫电子
to see the train wreck that is Cardiff Electric,
到时候  我们就让他们大开眼界
and when they do, we blow them away.
但巨人不在我们手上啊
But we don't have the Giant.
我偷来了  我给拿回来了
I stole it, took it. I got it back.
你
You--
你偷回来了
you stole it?
你真是疯了
You're crazy.
是啊
You're damn right.
八个月前  我是个苦逼的销售工程师
Eight months ago, I was a miserable sales engineer
一天最喜欢做的事就是下班回家
whose favorite part of the day was clocking out.
昨天  我闯进犯罪现场
Yesterday, I broke into a crime scene
偷回我出力建造的最先进的电脑
to steal the state-of-the-art computer that I helped create.
卡梅伦  天才程序员
Cameron, the brilliant programmer,
本来再过几个月就能大学毕业
months away from a college degree
在软件界大展拳脚  却退学
and a promising career in software, she dropped out,
最后入侵了国家银行的电脑
ended up hacking into the computers of a national bank.
约翰·博斯沃思  德州老好人
John Bosworth, Texas good ol' boy,
"我恨乔·米卡梅伦俱乐部"的主席
president of the "I Hate Joe MacMillan" fan club.
约翰·博斯沃思为了
John Bosworth hatched a plan
让项目得以继续
to embezzle thousands and thousands of dollars
策划挪用了大笔公款
just to keep this project alive.
你把我们都整疯了
You-- you made us all crazy,
别一副你突然清醒过来的样子
so don't act like you suddenly found sanity.
巨人在我们手里  万事俱备
We have the Giant. It is ready to go.
只欠...钱
The only thing we need is money.
什么
I'm sorry?
我们需要...
We-- we-- we need-- you know...
我们需要你拿钱  乔
we need your money, Joe.
这就是我的全部家当
This is all I have.
什么
What?
衣服  车  就是我的全部
These clothes, that car, that's all I have.
抱歉  戈登
I'm sorry, Gordon.
看来到底有人被我唬住了
I guess someone was buying my act after all.
车值多少钱
How much is the car worth?
-那车多漂亮啊  -别念叨了
- Such a beautiful car. - Let it go.
跟你说  唐娜  我现在势不可挡
Look, I'm telling you, Donna, I'm on a roll.
他们都同意了
They're both on board.
我还让乔卖了他的保时捷
I got Joe to sell his Porsche
这下我们有钱去展览会了
so now we've got enough money for COMDEX.
怎么回事
What's this?
我要跟你一起去
I'm going with you.
真的
You are?
唐娜  女儿们呢
Oh, Donna. What about the girls?
在我父母那儿  看来我是疯了
They're at my parents'. I guess I am crazy.
好消息  唐娜也要来
Good news-- Donna's coming.
太好了  多多益善
Wonderful. The more the merrier.
我们走之前还得去一个地方
We've gotta make one last stop before we go.
进来
Get inside.
来这儿可真蠢
Pretty stupid idea you coming.
巴瑞给你做律师吗
Barry's your lawyer?
不是
No.
不是的
巴瑞替我处理事务  但他是作为我朋友
Barry does paperwork, but he's my friend.
我还没提出  就给我保释了
Put up my bail before I even thought to ask.
他们绝不会相信是你一个人干的
They're never gonna believe you did this alone.
你没有那方面的技术知识
You don't have the technical knowledge.
你知道吗  那家银行
Did you know that damn bank
他们的拨入账户管理分时系统
was using a DEC-20 running TOPS
用的是DEC20主机  运行TOPS系统
for their dial-in account management timesharing system?
真的  你知道吗  如果你动作够快
I kid you not. Turns out, if you do it quick enough,
在异常处理程序被调用之前
before the exception handlers are invoked,
用control+C跳出用户程序
you can control-C out of the user program
你就会得到一个
and then you're left sitting with a terminal session
对账户有特殊权限的终端
on an account which has some pretty interesting privileges,
可以运行kermit协议
including running Kermit.
我有个好老师啊
Oh, I had a good teacher.
你来干嘛
Now, why'd you come?
我们要去计算机分销商展览了
We're going to COMDEX.
真的啊  你们怎么做到的
No kidding. How did you manage that?
使了点小坏吧
It's kind of a rogue operation.
本来就该如此
Well, that's just as it should be.
我没事的
I'll be all right.
快去吧
Oh, come on, now.
去展览会
Go to COMDEX.
把他们都打趴下
Knock 'em dead.
就算是为了我
Do that for me.
快走吧
Get the hell outta here.
好了  大家都准备好了吗
All right, everybody ready?
-嗯  -好了
- Yep. - We're good.
我们要去拉斯维加斯参加展览会喽
We're off to Vegas, COMDEX!
人人影视
倾情奉献
翻译
潇湘月影
七七
翻译
木浅薰
磁芯章鱼X
翻译
小花豆
森森爱上BOSS叔的草草
时间轴
Kallen 今
特效
宝宝
电脑狂人
第一季
第八集
校对&总监
草草
后期
饿得慌
顾问
大伟昔